Welcome to this section
on deploying and managing infrastructure at scale.
In this section, we'll see different ways
to deploy your workloads onto AWS.
And the first technology I wanna talk about
is CloudFormation.
So CloudFormation is such an important technology
in the AWS
because it is a declarative way
of outlining your AWS infrastructure, for any resources,
and most of them are supported.
So to give you a concrete example,
in CloudFormation, you would say,
"I want a security group.
I want two EC2 instances
that will be using that security group.
I also want an S3 bucket.
And I want a load balancer in front of all these machines."
Then CloudFormation
automatically creates all these things for you
in the right order
with the exact configuration that you specify.
So the benefits of using CloudFormation are multiple.
But the first one
is that all your infrastructure is as code.
That means that
you will never, ever create resources manually
like we've done in this course,
which is excellent for control.
And that means that anytime you do a changes
to how your AWS cloud is doing,
then it needs to be reviewed through code review,
which is a great way to operate in a cloud.
On top of things, there is a cost advantage,
because each resource within the stack
is going to get a tag that is going to be similar
to all the other resources created within the stack.
And you can also easily estimate the cost of your resources
using the CloudFormation templates.
And finally, thanks to CloudFormation,
you can have a saving strategy.
For example, you can say that in some environment,
you could automate the deletion of all the templates
at 5:00 PM,
which will delete all the associated resources
with that template,
and then recreate it at 9:00 AM or 8:00 AM safely.
And so therefore, you have cost savings
because you don't have any resources
between 5:00 PM and 8:00 AM.
With CloudFormation,
it's super easy to create and delete resources,
which is one of the biggest cloud principle.
Then for productivity.
So as I said, you're able to destroy
and recreate infrastructure on the fly.
It's also generating diagrams for you,
for your templates, as we'll see very quickly.
And there's declarative programming,
so you don't need to figure out
if you need to create a DynamoDB table first,
or an EC2 instance, or all these things together.
The CloudFormation template is smart enough
to figure out how to do things.
Finally, with CloudFormation, we don't reinvent the wheel.
So that means that we can leverage existing templates
on the web, we can leverage documentation,
and CloudFormation supports almost all AWS resources.
That means that everything we'll see in this course
is supported by CloudFormation,
and in case it isn't,
you can use something called a custom resource
for resources that are not supported.
So CloudFormation
really is the base of infrastructure as code on AWS.
So as I said, you could visualize a CloudFormation template,
and for this you would use the Application Composer service.
So I took the liberty
to use a WordPress CloudFormation stack,
and visualize it in Application Composer.
And as you can see, we can see all the resources
of our CloudFormation templates.
So we can see the ALBListener, the database security group,
the SQL database, different security groups,
launch configuration, application balancers, and so on.
But on top of it, we can see the relations
between all of these components
and how they're linked together,
which is very handy
when you want to understand your architecture diagrams.
So from an exam perspective,
CloudFormation is going to be used
when we have infrastructure as code,
when we need to repeat an architecture
in different environments, different regions,
or even different AWS accounts.
So that's it for me.
I will see you in the next lecture
for a short practice on CloudFormation.